DO NASCIMENTO BORGES, RAPHAEL

São Bernardo do Campo - SP

E-mail: raphael.n.borges@gmail.com | Celular: +55 (11) 99017-3638 LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raphael-do-nascimento-borges

GitHub: https://github.com/Rapha-Borges

SUMMARY

Student of Analysis and Systems Development at Uninter. I hold certifications as an AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner and Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations Associate, and I am mentored by Mateus Prado, an AWS TAM. With over 15 years of experience in Linux systems, I have actively participated in open-source projects. Currently, my focus is on specializing in Containers and Kubernetes through the LINUXtips Intensive Program in Containers and Kubernetes (PICK). My expertise encompasses network infrastructure, cloud services, container orchestration, complemented by practical experience in software development and database management.

EDUCATION

Associate Degree: Technology in Analysis and Systems Development – Uninter

LANGUAGES

English - Intermediate Level French - Basic Level Portuguese - Native

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staff Burger

Owner | October 2020 - February 2022 | Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Picanha Catering

Assistant | July 2018 - August 2019 | Luxembourg, Luxembourg

Grupo Contax

Technical Support | July 2013 - April 2015 | Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

COURSES AND ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCES

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS) – 2023
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Certified Foundations Associate - 2023
AWS Expert - LINUXTips - 34 hours - 2022
Demystifying Docker - LINUXTips - 12 hours - 2022
Python for Web Development - Alura - 85 hours - 2022
Python Enthusiast - Hashtag Treinamentos - 100 hours - 2022
Microsoft S2B Network and Systems Administration - PUC-RS – 2010

SKILLS

Containers and Orchestration: Kubernetes, Docker

Cloud and IaC: AWS, OCI, Terraform

Observability: Prometheus

Development: Python, Bash Script, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

CI/CD: Git, GitHub Actions

Network Infrastructure and Security:

- DNS (Domain Name System)
- OSI model (Open System Interconnection)
- Communication and Security Protocols (HTTP, HTTPS, TCP/IP, UDP, Stateful, Stateless)
- Load Balancer
- Firewall
- VPN (Virtual Private Network)
- CDN (Content Delivery Network)

Hardware and Operating Systems: Linux, macOS, Windows